Ernesto Garcia

Davis, CA 95616 ernesto.garcia.lb@gmail.com 209-592-8539

I am a highly-motivated full-stack web developer. My journey in the tech industry began after graduating from UCLA with a Bachelor's of Science in Neuroscience. Through many hours of bookreading and YouTube video-watching, I taught myself the basics of iOS programming. Because of the many technologies and languages I had not mastered, I joined the UC Davis Full-Stack Bootcamp to gain the skills to become a full-fledged developer.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Animal Care Technician II

Genentech - Dixon, CA August 2018 to Present

- Review and comply with all Standard Operating Procedures and quality assurance standards pertaining to animal husbandry
- Monitor animal health and welfare by performing daily health checks
- Perform animal husbandry duties to maintain quality and health of research animals
- Work closely with Veterinary Staff to treat a variety of health conditions
- Assist with animal genetic sample collection and other in vivo procedures
- Provide a variety of technical manipulations on mice, such as ear tagging, ear notching, tissue sampling, and identification techniques
- Euthanize laboratory mice using humane and ethical methods
- Received Genentech Recognition on September 9, 2019 due to excellent performance on weekend health observations and reporting

Logistics Backroom Team Member

Target - Davis, CA August 2017 to August 2018

- Process continuous flow of online orders
- · Locate all items from within store and package them according to corporate protocols
- Awarded November Employee of the Month
- Led Ship From Store team to be recognized by District Corporate office for exemplary performance

Lab Assistant

Arnold Lab, UCLA - Los Angeles, CA January 2015 to June 2016

My work at the Arnold Lab focused on mouse models of Klinefelter syndrome. We recorded their behaviors and correlated them with neuronal activity and genetic markers. My lab work was detail-oriented, with little room for error, and required me to perform lengthy, complicated protocols.

- Perform PCR analysis of genetic samples on a weekly basis
- Sort and classify hundreds of auditory patterns per week
- Weigh mice daily and record data to database

Clinic Assistant

Venice Family Clinic - Santa Monica, CA January 2014 to June 2016

- Record vitals and ensure the vitals were not outside healthy ranges
- Collaborate closely with nurses to ensure patients received exemplary care
- Prepare exam room for the doctor by gathering sterile tools needed for procedures

Education

Full Stack Web Developer Coding Boot Camp

University of California-Davis - Davis, CA March 2019 to August 2019

Bachelor's in Neuroscience

University of California-Los Angeles September 2012 to June 2016

Skills

Node.js, Express.js, React, JavaScript, Visual Studio Code, GitHub, HTTP & REST API, MongoDB, Mongoose, Sequelize, Bootstrap

Links

https://ernie1994.github.io

Publications

Roommate Finder

https://roommate-finder-67.herokuapp.com/

August 2019

Use this app to find someone to live with! Create an account to post a room or search for a room based on a few criteria.

This project utilized React, Express, Mongoose, and Passport. My main role was creating two form pages, one for posting a room and the other for searching for a room. I successfully completed both the frontend and backend aspects of these pages.

The frontend portion of the pages relied entirely on React, which included tracking the state of user input in a React-approved manner. The backend work was accomplished using Mongoose and by creating API routes and controller objects. I utilized Google's Firebase to store profile and room pictures.

I also created a Room Detail page, which displayed all the images associated with a room post, as well as the info of the user who posted the room.

The link to the GitHub repository is https://github.com/ernie1994/roommate.

Additional Information

- Graduated with "cum laude" honors
- Nominated to be TA for Full Stack Web Developer Coding Boot Camp